THE STORY
“Swinging off branches, playing in valleys”
“I should be coddled in mother's lap everyday”
“The nightingale that sings
from behind the tree”
“Should be with me as it reciprocates
with a 'koo' whenever I call her”
“Each day as it dawns”
“mother, I should walk in your footsteps”
“Swinging off branches, playing in valleys”
“I should be coddled in mother's lap everyday”
A good day of hunting, my dear?
Yes, it was rather.
Do you believe it?
It's amazing. Who's the artist?
What? This chit of a girl?
I want to have this little package
on our mantelpiece.
Edward.
- Yes, sir.
The Lady is giving you a token of
appreciation for your child’s song.
Take it, Loki.
At your service, Lady.
At your service, Lord.
Malli.
Loki, the money they have given you
was not for the song.
They’ve bought your daughter.
MALLI!
Malli.
Malli... Malli...
My child.
Please give me back my child.
I fall at your feet.
I beg you!
I beg you.
I fall at your feet.
Sergeant!
Do you comprehend the value
of the bullet in your barrel?
It was manufactured in an English factory
using English metals.
It crossed the 7 seas in an English vessel.
By the time it reached
the barrel of your gun
it cost One Pound.
One Pound Sterling!
And you would want to squander it on
brown rubbish?
Clear the road.
Please don’t take my child away
I’m begging you
Lady, please.
THE FIRE
OUTSKIRTS OF DELHI
Release our leader Lala Lajpat Rai!
Otherwise we’ll burn down this police station!
Of course not, sir.
We haven’t done anything to provoke them.
They are rioting here because
Lala Lajpat Rai has been arrested in Calcutta.
They’re rabid!
We need reinforcements NOW!
It's going to take another 7 hours.
Hold the line, damn it!
Let’s burn them down!
Arrest that bastard
and
bring him to me
You double-crosser!
You filthy traitor!
Good God!
That mob!
I was scared out of my wits, sir!
He scares me more.
BRITISH BARRACKS, DELHI
On the occasion of the annual
special officers' ceremony
only 3 have been deemed worthy
out of 75 candidates
for their exceptional contribution.
They are Philip Anderson,
Charles Langford,
Frank Poole.
As for the rest of you,
better luck next year.
Disperse!
THE WATER
Greetings, sir.
He is Mr Venkat Avadhani.
Special advisor to the Nizam.
Governor Scott is not in India.
State the purpose of your visit to Mr Edward.
When Governor Scott visited
Adilabad recently
he brought back with him a little girl.
Our Nawab has sent me to tell you
something about it.
It's regarding the girl we brought
from the Deccan.
It is our police department's opinion
that the girl be returned to her village.
It is our Nawab's opinion too-
Why so?
It is a Gond child that you've brought, sir.
- So?
- So what?
Do they have two horns on their head?
They are an innocent people, sir.
Even if you oppress them
they won't raise their voice.
But they have a trait.
They like staying in herds like sheep.
Even if one lamb goes missing
it causes them great distress.
This is why the herd has a shepherd.
He protects the herd with his life.
So this tribal is going to shoot down
the mighty British empire
with his bow and arrows.
So is this tribal going to take us down?
Don't misunderstand me.
I'm only trying to tell you about him.
The shepherd will travel however far
to retrieve the missing lamb.
Be it morning or night,
sun or rain, rocks, mountains,
valleys, peaks...
he will search anywhere and everywhere
for the missing lamb and will eventually find it.
If at that time the lamb is
in the tiger's mouth
he will break its teeth, pry its jaws open
and take the lamb back to its herd.
It seems that the shepherd has come
to Delhi to begin his hunt.
FOREST OUTSIDE DELHI
The trap is set.
Alert our brother.
Jangu, it's not a wolf.
It's a tiger.
Jangu!
I am using you for my need.
Forgive me, brother.
It’s been 6 months since we’ve come to Delhi.
We are doing everything we can to find Malli.
Do you think...
Malli is alive?
Akthar.
Where did you disappear off to?
There’s a lot of work.
Come on.
Give it to me.
Hey! You!
Greetings, sir.
The engine died on me again
what did you repair?
I’ve been kicking and kicking
and this damn thing won’t start.
Let me check, sir.
It's on reserve, sir.
I’m sorry.
What’s the bloody trick?
I didn't do anything, sir.
You removed something earlier
and attached it now
so that you can charge me again?
I didn’t do anything, sir.
You cheating bastard!
There's no fault of mine, sir.
Sir. Please forgive him, sir.
- I didn’t do anything, sir.
- Forgive him, sir.
Robert, please stop it.
It's not his fault.
This will never happen again, sir!
I beg you.
Oh God!
Son.
Careful, son.
- Brother, are you okay?
He is a monster.
Look how badly he has beaten him.
Why are you hiding your anger, son?
If they come to know the truth about me...
they will punish you all
for giving me shelter.
Even though I wasn’t born to you,
you are protecting me with your life.
I shouldn't cause you any harm.
Come what may, I'll never
let anyone know my true identity.
And that is the gist of it.
We have a hunter targeting
the Governor roaming free in Delhi.
We shouldn’t really be bothering about
imbecile tribals.
However our good friend the Nizam
who knows the prowess of these tribals
seems to think so.
And since this is a matter regarding
the Governor
we should act on it.
And with a good deal of bother.
- Alright, sir.
We will apprehend this bugger.
Though I would rather roast this swine
on a bed of coals.
Let us have the file, sir.
Well yes that is the catch, officer.
We have nothing on him.
You mean nothing?
Identifying features?
Criminal history?
It's quite an impossible task.
How the hell are we supposed to catch him?
Do they expect us to capture a tribal
with no criminal history?
The one that accomplishes the impossible
will be promoted to the rank
of special officer.
Do you want him dead or alive?
I can vouch for this man.
If anyone can do the job, it’s him.
You bring him dead, you receive a bounty.
You bring him alive,
you will be promoted to special officer.
We don't need to search all over Delhi.
What he wants is in the Scott's bungalow.
He will come there.
He will be in those surroundings.
How will we find him among
so many people?
He will think that his enemy's
enemies are his friends.
We should also act like
we are against the British.
Before we do that
find out where all the revolutionaries
and rebels have their meetings.
Bow your heads before you go inside
and stay that way until you come out.
Do your job and leave.
Show me your IDs.
You.
ID.
I forgot, sir.
Stop, stop it.
Stop.
- Forgive me, sir.
- Why are you hitting him like that?
- He's forgotten his ID, ma'am.
That doesn't give you the right
to treat him like an animal.
Sorry ma'am.
She seems kind-hearted.
We might find a way in if we befriend that girl.
Freedom is our birthright.
We don't have to beg for our rights.
Let's start teaching our children about
the idea of revolution.
Let's start teaching our children
about revolution.
One moment.
Why beat around the bush?
We should hit them where it hurts.
Let's kill Governor Scott.
Why not just kill King George?
He is saying that we should kill Scott.
I said that it would be better
to kill King George.
Brother is it true?
Is it possible to kill Scott?
Why can't we kill him?
What's your name, brother?
My name is Lacchu.
Scott has done a grave injustice
to us, brother.
We have come with our brother.
Can you please help us?
Sure, I will.
Where's your brother?
I will take you there, brother.
Come on.
We have been roaming around
for so many days, brother.
We didn't know whom to ask for help.
You appeared like a God-
I am an officer on duty. Do a casual
check and let us pass through.
ID.
He’s an officer.
- Yes, sir.
Is this what you’ve bought?
It’s not fresh at all.
I will get you a nice fish.
Give me one anna.
- Hey, Chotu. Come here.
I’ll be right back.
Brother! Brother!
What happened?
A policeman.
He chased me like a cheetah.
- A police officer?
- Jangu
Come here.
Tell me.
He looked like one of us.
So I spoke to him.
When I got to know that he is a police officer,
I escaped from him.
If word gets out we’ll all be killed.
Don’t let anyone see you.
Don't come out until I tell you.
Go.
Raju, once you step on a snake's shadow,
you never find it again.
We won't find him.
The promise we have made to the village
will not be fulfilled.
We won't find Malli.
Save me! Save me!
Does anybody have anything?
A boat or a rope?
Let's save the child.
- Are you mad?
- No, please don't say that.
He's a child. Let's help him.
Save me! Save me!
- Raju
- Akhtar.
“Between a tiger and a hunter”
“Between a head and the guillotine”
“Between a wildfire”
“and a storm”
“Between the sun and the cloud”
“A new friendship”
“This is an unforeseen turn of fate”
“Which has culminated in this friendship”
“It’s yet to be seen if this will end
in bloodshed”
“Friendship between an erupting
volcano and a wild storm”
“Friendship between freewill and destiny”
“This friendship is between opposites”
My father.
- Greetings.
- My mother.
Have this.
How many times should I tell you
not to eat with your left hand?
How does it matter to hunger
what hand you eat with, Ammi?
What happened?
Nothing. I just remembered something.
Chandini Chowk?
Do you think that is enough
to satisfy his hunger, Raju?
Don't cast evil eye on him, uncle.
“An unpredictable gust of wind”
“Has erased the distance between both of them”
“Will their rivalry ever come to the forefront?”
“Walking the same path”
“But searching for different things”
“Won’t this friendship break
one day in the form of betrayal?”
“In the deceptive game of destiny”
“It is impossible to know what lies
around the next turn”
“This is an unforeseen turn of fate”
“Which has culminated in this friendship”
“It’s yet to be seen if this will end
in bloodshed”
Brother.
What is that?
Why are you blushing, brother?
Did someone special give you this?
I thought so.
What’s her name?
Seetha.
Ram and Seetha.
“One hand protects”
“And the other kills”
- Brother! Pull harder!
“East and west have come together”
“When the unpredictable fight happens”
“Who will decide whose victory it is?”
“This is an unforeseen turn of fate”
“Which has culminated in this friendship”
“It’s yet to be seen if this will end in bloodshed”
Brother, what’s that in your hand?
He is missing.
I'm trying to find him.
Why didn't you ask me?
Yeah, right? Why didn't I ask you?
Show me, brother. If he is from
around here I'll recognize him instantly.
Is she that beautiful?
She is very beautiful.
Why don’t you speak to her?
I would like to.
But I can't find a way.
Brother, to speak to a girl
you shouldn't try to find a way.
You should pave your own path.
You drive the bike.
I’ll show you the way.
Akhtar, stop here.
Stop here? But why?
Because the car will stop here.
She’ll stop here?
Oh no.
How did you know that the car
would stop here?
I threw some nails on the road.
The tyres have gotten punctured.
Wow! You’re so clever.
Now I will repair her tyres.
She will thank me.
That way, we can speak to each other.
Is that it?
Excuse me! Could you help?
My tyres have gone flat.
Yes, ma’am! Our shop is very close by
I will patch up your tyres in 5 minutes
He means it will take at least 5 hours.
Oh!
Is there a bus stop or a tram station nearby?
She is asking if there’s a bus stop
or a tram station nearby.
Yes. Very close-
- Shake your head
Perhaps you can ask him for a ride.
Oh. Are you going that way?
She is asking if you’re going that way.
Will you give her a lift?
- No.
- Nod your head.
Oh. That’s a yes?
- Yes.
- Wonderful, let me get my things.
Can you take me to the market please?
- Market?
Thank you.
These are very small, madam.
Your house is very big.
Your... house... house...
Oh you mean our house is big?
it is but
not really beautiful
you know
Not like a real home.
Can I come to your house, madam?
Can I see your house?
I'm sorry, I can’t understand
what you are saying.
What's your name, madam?
Sorry?
Your name
Name
- Oh, you mean my name?
What’s your name, madam?
Oh, don't call me madam.
It's just Jenny, yes?
Such a big name!
How do I call you in short, madam?
Don't call me madam.
It is just Jenny
...yes?
Don't call me memsaab.
It is just Jenny, yes.
Oh, no.
This isn’t for you.
It’s for kids.
Oh.
It’s not for me. there is
a small girl staying with us
Malli.
This is for her.
How much does this cost?
I need to make something.
This will go well with that dress.
Oh
How beautiful!
She is going to love it.
Did you make this?
No, I mean
No. I made it.
Good lord you are safe
we were worried about you, ma'am.
Why on earth? I am perfectly alright.
Going out with a native could be
dangerous, ma'am.
Please come with me.
Give me a minute.
- Alright, ma’am.
I would love to see you again.
There is a party at the Gymkhana Club.
This is the invitation.
Please do try to come.
Bye.
Hello Malli.
Look what I bought for you.
Do you like it?
What about a toy elephant?
A bangle?
Brother Brother
I spoke to her.
Yeah? How's your girlfriend?
What?
I mean your lover, girlfriend
sweetheart, darling.
Don’t say that. It’s wrong.
Wrong?
If she didn’t like you
would she hop on your bike?
I don't know.
Tell me what to do next.
Okay. What's her name?
It's a very big name
but I’ve memorised it.
'Don't call me memsaab,
it is Jenny yes'
Don't call me memsaab, it is Jenny yes.
That’s not her name.
It means that 'don't call me madam,
just Jenny will do'
Oh, Jenny.
It's a small name only.
Okay. What else did you talk about?
We spoke a lot.
But while she was leaving
she said 'party... come'
or something like that.
She invited you to a party?
That too on the first meeting?
Where, when?
- Here, she gave me this.
Feb 14th... hey, it’s today... right now.
Stop eating, leave now.
Alone? Why don't you come along?
Okay. I'll come.
Come.
What? Like this?
It’s been so long since I’ve been to a party.
I simply can’t wait to dance.
If you are in need of a dance partner, Jennifer
You needn’t look any further.
You are looking at the best dancer
around here.
- Oh yes.
- I second that.
I don’t mind teaching you some good moves-
Akhtar, you look amazing in your suit.
He wanted to look his best
when he met you.
Come, let’s join the party.
You both carry on. I’ll join you in a while.
Brother
- Hi, Jenny.
- Hi, Maggie, how’s Max?
- Oh, he’s great.
- Wonderful.
Would you like to dance?
I can see that you do.
Come on, we must dance.
Left hand here...
Your right hand here
Step back.
Back, side. Done. You’ve got it.
You’re a natural.
- Did you give the bangle, madam?
- I can’t understand what you are saying.
- Can I come to your house?
- I’m sorry.
Are you okay?
- I’m fine.
Oh, I’m so sorry, don’t worry,
it’ll come out.
I am so sorry.
Every damn wanker thinks he can dance.
What do you think of yourself, huh!?
You country oaf.
Look at them.
- Wait.
Look at all these brown buggers.
What do they know about art?
About finesse.
About dance.
Tango.
Swing.
Flamenco.
Can you do any of these? Huh?
Not salsa. Not Flamenco, my brother.
Do you know 'Naatu'?
What is ‘Naatu’?
“Like an aggressive bull jumping
in the dust of the fields”
“Like the lead dancer dancing
at a local goddess’s festival”
“Like playing with the stick while wearing
wooden slippers”
“Like a gang of young boys assembling
under the shade of a banyan tree”
“Like eating a jowar roti with a chilli”
“Listen to my song.
Listen to my song”
“Listen to my song”
“Naatu Naatu Naatu”
“Crazy Naatu”
“Wild Naatu”
“Naatu like a green chilli”
“Naatu like a sharp dagger”
I’ve had enough of this nonsense!
You two! Out!
No Jake. I’ve had enough of your bullying.
Go away!
Go!
“Like beating a drum which makes
your heart beat faster”
“Like the shrill voice of a bird
which can make your ears ring”
“Like singing a song which can
make your fingers snap in rhythm”
“Like the wild dance when there is a fast rhythm”
“Like dancing which makes your body sweat”
“Listen to my song”
“Naatu Naatu Naatu”
“Crazy Naatu”
“Wild Naatu”
“Naatu like a green chilli”
“Naatu like a sharp dagger”
This is disgusting! This is filthy!
Jenny!
“Dance in such a way that the blood
in your body”
“Jumps violently which will make
the earth tremble”
“Naatu naatu naatu”
“The life force inside you should dance with joy”
“So jump until the dust rises into the air”
“Naatu Naatu Naatu”
- Ram! Ram! Ram!
- No.
Come on, Akhtar.
Yes!
Oh God!
Get down now.
You are so heavy.
How much further should I carry you?
- Don't say that brother! I beg you.
If I take another step my legs will fall off.
Please carry me a little longer.
Why did you dance so much
if you were in so much pain?
I don't know.
When you looked at me like that
I just felt like competing with you.
Are you hurt? What’s happened?
Is he alright?
He’s got a bad cramp.
Can you drop him at New Bazaar?
Of course.
Get in.
Would you like to come to my place
for a coffee?
Before I drop you home.
She is inviting you to her house
for a cup of coffee.
I would offer to drop you too,
but it’s only a two seater.
No problem, I am waiting for a friend.
Alright, bye.
The first time we met him,
he rested his hand on my shoulder.
I remember clearly.
I noticed paint in his nails.
He is definitely a painter.
Search that way, uncle.
Listen, did you see him?
- No.
Have you seen him anywhere?
Good morning, Thomas.
How are you today?
I'm very good. Thank you so much.
How about you?
I'm good, thank you.
Open the gates.
The second gate only opens
once the first is closed.
I don’t understand the need for
such elaborate security measures.
Overwhelming, huh?
Uncle Scott is coming back
from London in two days.
he has been knighted by the King.
Aunt Cathy wants to throw a grand party
on his arrival.
Everything is checked, sir.
Have you checked every door?
Hundreds of people are working round
the clock to make sure everything is smooth-
- I don't want any hangups, officer.
- Yes, sir.
See these lights? They were commissioned-
- What the hell are you doing here?
Robert, what are you doing?
He is with me.
He is here by my invitation.
Let him go.
Servants can’t use the main entrance, ma'am.
I’ll show him the back entrance.
Robert! Robert!
He is not a servant.
He is my friend.
Let him go.
As you wish, ma'am.
That was appalling behavior.
I apologize.
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
You're fine, right?
Okay
let's forget about him.
I was really looking forward to this.
I have so much that
I wanted to show you.
Please. Come, sit down.
This is my room
and these are my paintings.
What do you think?
Please. Sit down.
Your dance at the party
took my breath away.
It was amazing.
Thank you, madam.
Jenny.
Thank you, Jenny.
It was overwhelming.
The beat pulsating through your body
the flying feet, the flashing eyes...
the eyes.
Akhtar
your deep expressive eyes always seem
like they are searching for something.
Jenny, I can't understand
what you are saying.
“O Mynah, I won't paint your wings,
come to me”
“O crescent moon, I won't decorate you
with peacock feathers, come to me”
I'm hungry
Oh... I’m so sorry...
I will get you something to eat.
“We should play along as we eat heartily”
“O wandering rabbit, come to me”
“Swinging off branches, playing in valleys”
“I should be coddled in mother's lap everyday”
Maggie.
- Yes, ma'am...
Malli...
Brother!
Brother.
Don't cry, Malli.
I'm here, right?
I don’t want to stay here anymore.
Take me with you.
Don't shout. If the police hear us
it won't be good for us.
Listen, I’ll come back to take you from here.
Brother.
So you are not taking me with you now?
There is no other way, Malli.
No! I want to go home.
Take me away now!
I won't be here for another moment.
Won’t you listen to me?
Listen to me, Malli-
- I won't listen to you.
- Don't make noise.
If somebody hears us,
we will get caught.
I don't know all that.
Brother. Brother.
Please don't leave me here.
I want to go back to my mother.
Please take me home.
“Swinging off branches, playing in valleys”
“All of it will be in front of your eyes
if you close them”
“The nightingale singing behind the tree”
“will appear in your heart
whenever you close your eyes”
“The trees and tender leaves will see today
from the stone enclosure around them”
“If you are patient enough to close
your eyes for a moment”
“The day will soon come when you will be free”
Mother
Don't these white women bear children?
Don't they know what pain is?
They took away a child and
locked her in a cage.
Even if they cry once
they will understand
how painful tears are.
What shall we do now?
We need to get Malli back.
We shouldn't be scared anymore.
We should surge forward.
Whoever comes in our way
should be eliminated.
Jangu, where is Lacchu?
Where is your brother?
My brother is on a mission, and
he is not going to be captured.
Especially not by traitors like you.
A dog can never hunt down a tiger.
Nobody is coming, sister.
Seetha...
Did you receive any message from Ram?
- No, uncle.
- Has he at least written a letter?
What is this?
It has been 4 years since he left.
How much longer should
we wait for him?
Does he even remember us?
Does he remember his village, his land,
the promise he has made us?
Forget about us.
Does he at least remember you?
You will keep experiencing this pain until
I get an answer.
Tell me...
where is your brother?
Banded Krait snake.
Even the English don't have a cure
for its venom.
You are going to die within an hour.
It will take you a day to untie these knots.
Live your life.
The family is organizing an event
to celebrate Scott's return.
We should execute our plan tonight at any cost.
If we miss this oppurtunity,
we might not get another one.
The truck is working properly, right?
I've tested it again.
It's in good condition.
We should storm in as soon as
the arrangements are done.
Jangu, you remember everything, right?
I've memorized everything, brother.
Let’s go.
Brother, when are you going to reach
the bungalow?
I'll come at 8’o clock.
Peddayya, ask Abbajaan to inspect
the vehicle again.
Jangu, go right now and memorize
the sound of the gates.
What happened?
Brother.
Brother, what happened?
Banded Krait snake.
Peddayya, I need a burning piece of coal.
Jangu, get a datura root.
Brother. Brother.
You’ll be fine.
“East and west are engaged in a tug of war”
“One’s a deadly weapon”
“The other’s a bringer of death”
“Once the veil is lifted,
won’t there be a destructive war?”
Looks like the poison has taken effect.
Why are you removing the holy thread?
Don’t do it, brother.
Removing it will bring you problems.
Brother needs it more than me.
You guys leave.
Don’t close your eyes, brother.
I’m here with you.
You’ll be fine.
You’re out of danger now.
The antidote is working against the poison.
You will have recovered completely
by tomorrow.
I have some work.
I'll be back.
Brother.
If I had a choice I would stay with you.
But I have to go.
Brother
I’ve hidden a truth from you.
I'm not Akhtar. I'm not a muslim.
I’m Bheem. Son of the Gonds.
They took away a little girl
from our village.
We didn't know what to do.
We didn't know how to save her.
We didn't know whom to trust.
That is why I put on this disguise.
I wanted to seek your help
on many occasions.
But I didn't do so because
I didn’t want to put your life in danger.
Not because I don’t trust you.
We are going tonight to rescue Malli.
If we get out safely
I will come meet you again.
If I don't make it...
I have your friendship which is more
precious than my life.
I'll die with pride.
Until next time, brother.
‘I have your friendship which is more
precious than my life.’
‘Brother needs it more than me.’
What a grand party Aunt Catherine has put on.
Come, let’s join her.
- Let’s stay with our friends.
Lady Buxton...
Pleasure as always.
- Thank you.
And what a magnificent event
you have organized, ma'am.
Brother.
Malli.
Brother!
Akhtar.
Brother... why are you
wearing this uniform?
I’m arresting you for the crimes you’ve committed
against the British Government.
Brother, are you a police officer?
Are you really a police officer?
I can't believe it.
Surrender, Akhtar.
I swear on my mother.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I told you about my problems, right?
Brother, brother, I really
didn't do anything wrong.
Just look into my eyes once, brother.
Brother
I haven’t done anything wrong!
We came here for our sister.
She is a small child.
I’m begging you.
Let us take our sister home.
Let us take our sister home!
I'm not going to ask you again, Akhtar.
Surrender.
Surrender!
Why are you talking like this?
I'm not able to bear seeing you
like this, brother
Brother, aren’t you one of us?
You’re one of us, right?
If we don't arrest him by then
the governor will skin us alive.
- Brother!
- Shut up, you insolent brat!
- Brother.
- Malli.
Brother.
Surrender, Bheem.
Surrender if you want Malli to stay alive.
Brother!
“This is an unforeseen turn of fate”
“Which has culminated in this friendship”
“It’s yet to be seen if this will end
in bloodshed”
We don’t know anything, sir.
They’ve escaped, sir.
It's as though they have vanished, sir.
Nobody knows anything about their whereabouts.
We've got the big fish, sergeant.
Just a matter of time before
we flush the rats out of their holes.
Let's go.
- Yes sir.
Move out!
Owing to his outstanding performance
in the field,
and for capturing a dangerous criminal,
Mr A Rama Raju is being awarded
the rank of special officer.
First line point.
Second line point.
Attack.
Move.
Change.
Turn and point.
Load.
Relax.
Point your weapons.
Second line point.
First line point.
Final position.
Second line, point your weapons, move.
Third line, point your weapons, move.
Crawl faster.
Mani.
- Baba.
This drill should be done in 15 seconds.
- Okay, sir.
Load.
Baba,
these wooden rifles are only
for practice, right?
We have learned how to wield the weapon.
Our blood is boiling to shoot a real bullet.
When will you give us real rifles?
Do you know the value of this bullet?
It costs 15 rupees.
But an Englishman once explained
what its real value is.
To the people of the village of Paalakurthi,
these are the government's orders.
Since a very long time the villagers haven't been
paying any taxes citing floods as a reason.
When a British officer came here
to investigate this
your village head Singavarapu Malla Reddy
manhandled him.
This is a heinous crime.
For the crime of sedition,
the criminal has been sentenced to death.
Soldier.
Do you understand how valuable
the bullet in your gun is?
It was manufactured by an Englishman.
At full pay.
It made its way here on an English ship.
By the time that single bullet has made
its way to the barrel of your gun
it has cost the crown 6 shillings.
You don’t waste it on peasant stock.
Find another way, soldier.
Yes, sir.
He said that an Indian’s life
is not worth a bullet.
So how will this bullet earn its value?
When it comes out of your gun
and pierces an Englishman’s heart.
When that flaming bullet will bathe
in his blood.
Then... Only then this bullet
will earn its value.
The name of that value is
Freedom.
When I'm sure that you won't miss
even one shot.
I will give you the bullets
Keep practicing until then.
Hey!
How many times did I tell you
not to eat with your left hand?
It will get done faster this way, mother.
Ram.
- Uncle.
- Come, Venkateswarulu.
- Brother take this...
Seetha, why are you always here?
Don't you ever go home?
Wherever there is Ram,
I'll be there.
I don't know if she will become
my daughter-in-law
but she is my daughter already.
You're building an army here.
But you've sent me into
the police force.
I want to be here with you, Baba.
No. It is necessary that you be there.
We need their inside information.
Okay. What do we do now?
We will need weapons
once the training is done.
All you have is one rifle and a few bullets.
How many people will you give them to?
Every bullet has the name
of the person it is going to kill.
Every rifle has on it the name of the person
who is going to shoot it.
They will come, Venkateswarlu.
The weapons will come themselves
in search of their battle.
Turn and point. Load.
Rest the rifle properly on your shoulder.
What happened?
Down.
What is this?
Last night...
I fired your rifle, Baba.
Do you think it is a toy?
Is it a toy?
I gave it to him, Baba.
Seetha!
I gave it to him.
But Ram fired really well.
Let me show you.
Come.
There.
Rama.
Did you shoot from those boulders?
No, Baba.
Then?
From there, Baba.
Baba, it was a mistake...
I won’t do it again.
The weapon is ready, Venkateswarlu.
Our son?
Take cover.
Venkata Rama Raju... Surrender.
Otherwise, we will shoot down everyone.
We won’t spare anyone-
Let's fight, Baba.
Let's fight!
This isn't the time to fight, Ranga.
We need to save the villagers first.
Take everyone to the small bridge.
- Okay, Baba.
We scared him, sir.
Venkata Rama Raju.
- Go.
Surr-
Faster! That way.
Go.
Fast.
Move.
I'll stop them from there.
On my signal lead everyone into the forest.
Lay low in Maavullamma valley.
These Englishmen can’t reach there. Careful.
Dear.
What about you?
Sarojini.
I am my battle.
And half of that is yours.
Rama!
Stop.
Down!
I told you to be with your mother.
Why did you come here?
He has got good cover, sir.
He is not letting us advance.
Baba.
Down Hide.
Aunt.
Rama
Will you increase the value of the bullet?
Your aim should be precise.
Take it.
Load.
Aim.
Shoot.
Down.
Move. Move. Fast.
Chinna!
Mother!
Load.
Baba, mother.
Brother, Baba!
Load!
Aim.
Shoot.
We have to change the strategy.
Back.
Fall back!
Baba.
Did you see that?
Just one rifle and how all of them
have fallen back?
Just imagine...
...If every person had a weapon
...then they would go back to their
country for good.
Give me your word, Ram.
Promise me that you will give
every person a weapon.
Dear Seetha, how are you?
Everything is going according to the plan.
Guns are sent to different parts of the country
from the barracks that I'm working in.
And each time there's a consignment,
they choose an officer to transport it safely.
I'm going to get that opportunity
very soon.
The weapons are within reach.
But why is my heart heavy, Seetha?
I'm hurting the people whose freedom
I'm fighting for.
I have betrayed my closest friend.
I am nearing my goal
But am I losing my way?
I am unable to understand.
I wish you were with me.
One bastard did this
and all of you could do nothing.
Shame on you!
I appreciate you, young man.
Your service to the crown
has been duly noted.
Thank you, sir.
I want this bastard punished
in such a way that
no person will ever rise up
against the British.
Oh I want to watch it, darling.
I want to see him bleed.
And so you shall.
Flog him publicly!
Flog him till he falls to his knees
confessing his crime of daring
to rise against us.
And begs for mercy.
Sir.
The criminal who tried to break into
Governor Scott's palace
will be publicly flogged tomorrow.
It is the Governor's orders
that everybody be present.
This criminal is now going to fall
to his knees
and confess to his crimes
and he is going to plead the Governor
for mercy.
If he fails to do so,
he will be punished severely.
Kneel down.
Kneel down, Bheem!
There's hardly any blood.
Hit him harder.
A few lashes and the bugger's buckled.
But he barely even cried out loud.
And where's the blood?
I was expecting a pool at his feet.
He didn't kneel.
He didn't kneel!
Officer!
Try this one.
Use it on the pillar first, officer.
Let the wretch see how it will rip him.
Aren't you quite vicious, my dear?
This isn't going to stop, Bheem.
If you don't kneel down you will be killed.
Kneel and confess to your crimes.
Save your own life.
Bheema, the earth which has given
birth to you,
the trees which give you air to breathe,
your gond tribe which has given you
a name are talking to you.
Can you hear it?
“O komuram bheem, O komuram bheem”
“You should stoke the fire in your heart”
“You should burn like the flaming sun”
Make that bastard kneel now!
“Should you fall at your oppressor's feet
like a slave...”
“you are no more a child of the forest”
“If you bow your head to unjust rule”
“you could not have been born
to the forest.”
“O komuram bheem, O komuram bheem”
“You should stoke the fire in your heart”
“Will you scream in pain
when the whip splits your skin?”
“Will you tremble with fear
at the mere sight of blood?”
“If you get scared and shed a tear”
“how can you say that you’ve had
Mother Earth's breastmilk?”
“O komuram bheem, O komuram bheem”
“You should stoke the fire in your heart”
“Your heart's blood which flows
like a stream”
“look - it is like vermilion on
Mother earth's forehead”
“It is like sacred red paint on Mother's feet”
“It shines like the smile on Mother's lips”
“O komuram bheem, O komuram bheem”
“You have given your life as a gift
to Mother Earth”
“O komuram bheem”
Reinforcements!
Raju, you’ve been appointed as the incharge
for the guns’ consignment’s delivery.
Look.
The consignment will be shipped in 2 days.
‘Promise me that you will give
every person a weapon.’
Bheem is going to be hanged
the day after tomorrow.
I should get the place changed
from the jail.
To the bank of Yamuna river.
What are you saying?
Why... why would you want to shift
the hanging location?
Only from there I will be able to free Bheem.
Raju.
What is this business of freeing Bheem?
I should also free Malli
and hand her over to Bheem
Bheem? Malli?
Are you in your senses?
It has never been more clear to me, uncle.
All this while I was prepared to sacrifice
anything to achieve freedom for our country.
I thought Bheem would also be
one among them.
But today I’ve realized...
Bheem is not merely a sacrificial lamb.
He is a volcano.
I was under the impression that guns
would bring us freedom.
But Bheem inspired everyone
with just a song.
What about you?
You've striven so much to achieve your goal.
Will you forego all of that
when it is within your reach?
Will you sacrifice 15 years of hardwork-
- I will bear it for another 25 years.
But I won't sacrifice Bheem for my goal.
Baba told me to give a weapon
to every person.
But Bheem's emotion has turned
each person into a weapon.
I will give that emotion to the people.
Think about it, Raju.
It is very dangerous
you could lose your life.
I will die gladly, uncle.
I want the best hangman for the job.
I want to see his neck drawn out tight
and his eyes bulge and pop
just before his neck snaps.
Yes, sir.
But I doubt you will see fear in his eyes.
I mean
the fear which didn't appear
while he was being whipped violently
will not appear even in the face of death.
- Yes.
And what was blatantly obvious was
your abject failure
at bringing this brute to his knees.
I'm sorry to have disappointed you, sir.
Give me one more opportunity.
Let us hang him in front of Malli
for whom he has come this far...
All of the world's fear will then
be seen in his eyes.
I see you have learnt the ways
of the empire, young man.
Keep the flag flying.
- Yes sir.
Have him ready for hanging by 4AM
and get that wretched child here by 5.
- If I may, sir.
- Yes.
If you hang him here the people
will make him a martyr.
Temples will be built on his grave.
We must take him away.
To the banks of the river Yamuna.
If we hang him there we can dispose of
his corpse discreetly.
Take care. Load them carefully.
Be alert, officers. I want no hiccups
on this mission.
Yes, sir.
What are you doing?
- Help.
- Go there! Get back!
Back.
All arrangements have been made, sir.
Should be quite the spectacle.
I appreciate your effort, my boy.
Thank you, sir.
You had arrested my brother, right?
Where is he now?
Tell me, brother.
Go faster!
I said faster, damn it!
Bring me those treacherous scum alive.
Or I will skin every last one of you.
Brother.
Brother!!
Malli!
I'll be back
Without you... I...
Seetha
A part of me will always be with you.
Seetha, my courage drives me.
But it is your courage
which will make me win.
Grandfather.. uncle... brother...
I'm giving my word to the entire village.
I will give weapons to every hand
which is itching to revolt.
Only after that will I come back!
I swear on mother Godavari!
- Vande mataram!
It’s been months, Edward.
This jungle rat
Bheem
is still proving elusive.
We are very close, sir.
From the hanging point
his only means of escape is to Agra.
And we are sealing it off.
We are combing it area by area...
...inch by inch...
Shutting it down.
The only place he can be
possibly hiding now is Hathras.
Keep at it.
Meanwhile
let’s pay our special guest a visit. Shall we?
As you ordered, we are feeding him
only once a week, sir.
Just enough to keep him alive
and feel the pain.
Like these filth?
- Oh no, sir. Much worse than them.
He’d be so starved,
he’d be gnawing at his chains.
Exercising? With only days to live?
What do you hope to achieve?
Still chasing your impossible dream
even with death staring you in the face?
You have every right to work
but not to expect the result.
Let not the result be your motive,
nor let your attachment be to inaction.
I don’t care about the result.
I will be moving towards my goal
until my last breath.
Load.
Aim.
Shoot.
Is that so?
Let’s see how you move after this.
Throw him in the solitary cell.
It's been 2 days since we came here.
It's not good to stay in one place
for so long.
We need to leave after midnight.
Where will we go?
There is no place to hide.
Don't worry, Peddayya.
We will find a way.
I’m hungry, brother.
Oh God. The only thing we are able to give
a hungry child is some water.
Jangu.
It is getting very difficult.
Buying even a grain of rice
is seeming impossible.
These dangerous criminals
have escaped their execution, and are at large.
Report to the nearest police station
if you find anyone acting suspicious.
Wake up!
- That way.
- Go, go...
They are here.
Inspector, I want you to search that room.
There are many policemen outside.
Yes, sir.
I want the names and addresses of everybody.
Check in that room also.
Sir, please help us.
Please help me take them to the hospital.
My people have been infected
with smallpox.
What?
- Smallpox, sir... smallpox.
Smallpox.
What’s in the bag?
They have smallpox, sir.
Smallpox!?
Are you sure?
- Masoochi is smallpox, sir.
This place is infected! Everyone out!
I beg you, sir. Please help us.
- Get away from me, you diseased rat.
Everyone out! Out!
It's okay.
I'm fine.
You said smallpox. Who has it?
Nobody.
I just said that to help you from the police.
My fiancee always says that
we should help other people.
Please come.
I overheard you earlier...
Children shouldn't know hunger...
Even food feels bad.
We are indebted to you.
You have helped us without
knowing who we are.
Who are you?
My name is Seetha.
I'm from near Visakhapatnam.
I have come here for my fiancee.
Oh, really? Where does your fiancee live?
Delhi.
He is working as a police inspector
for the British.
- What is her name?
- Seetha.
Oh. Please don't be worried.
What my fiancee is doing is not just a job.
It’s a revolution.
Rama
to attain your goal you should be ready
to face any kind of obstacle.
Whatever happens don’t forget your goal.
Surround them from all sides.
Bastard! You thought you could take on us?
See the dog bleed.
Load.
Aim.
Shoot!
“Let the blue sky be painted
with fiery red embers”
“Let my battlecries be the war sounds
that will annihilate the enemy.”
But then did he get the weapons?
He was very close to getting them...
but in the process he had to betray
his closest friend and arrest him for the British.
He couldn’t live with himself.
He was unable to understand whether
what he was doing was right or wrong.
He finally decided to save his friend,
come what may.
And he did save him.
But he got caught while doing it.
I’ve received this letter from the government.
He is going to be hanged in two days.
They’ve asked me to come collect his body-
I came for Malli.
But your fiancee came for the land.
The tribal that I am
I couldn't understand.
I beat him with these hands.
I left my closest friend to die.
Seetha shouldn't go looking for Ram.
Ram should come to wherever Seetha is.
I will bring him to you.
You've fed us.
I'm giving you my word now.
I'll bring back your Ram
even if I have to lay down my life.
This is the whole barracks.
The jail is at the end of the barracks.
Be careful.
Bheem. Bheem.
- Brother.
- Bheem.
Bheem, why did you come here?
Forgive me, brother.
I didn’t realise that you were working towards
such a great cause.
- I shouldn’t have-
- Calm down.
Bheem.
Who told you?
Seetha...
Did you meet Seetha?
She opened my eyes to the truth.
I promised Seetha that I would
bring back her Ram.
Even if I have to burn down this Lanka,
I will take you to her.
Come, brother.
“Between a tiger and a hunter”
“Between a head and the guillotine”
“Between a wildfire”
“and a storm”
“Between the sun and the cloud”
“Friendship”
Surround them from all sides.
Spread out.
Surround. Surround.
“This is an unforeseen turn of fate”
“Which has culminated in this friendship”
Where did they go?
What the hell is going on here?
“Friendship between an erupting
volcano and a wild storm”
“Friendship between freewill and destiny”
“This friendship is between opposites”
- What’s going on, Edward?
- We arrived a bit late, sir.
They escaped into the forest.
- They’ve done what?
But they are still in the barracks.
Don’t follow them blindly.
Take the specials forces
and nail the bastards.
One more thing.
Don’t shoot until you’re close enough
to confirm a kill.
Absolutely, sir.
Call the special forces.
Fire!
Sir, Edward here.
Hold your fire!
What the hell is going on out there?
We thought we had them surrounded, sir.
But now there are arrows coming
out of everywhere.
We’re losing men, sir.
Damn them all!
I’m sending additional troops.
Do not let them escape!
Yes, sir.
More troops are on the way.
We are getting reinforcements.
Don't let them escape.
More troops are on the way.
Edward!
I promised my father
that I will give everyone a weapon.
Turn on the searchlights.
I've made a promise to mother Godavari
that I will come back only after
I get the weapons.
Turn on those lights.
“Raama, the descendant of Raghu lineage”
“is the greatest of all warriors
and his charm as the emperor is unmatched”
There is no more running away,
This is the time to make you run.
“Raama, the descendant of Raghu lineage”
“is the greatest of all warriors
and his charm as the emperor is unmatched”
Get away from the fire!
Get back!
Good God.
“His bow is as powerful as Lord Shiva’s”
“the sound of which scares
his enemies to death”
“Raama, the descendant of Raghu lineage”
“is the greatest of all warriors
and his charm as the emperor is unmatched”
“Raama, the descendant of Raghu lineage”
“is the greatest of all warriors
and his charm as the emperor is unmatched”
“Raama, the descendant of Raghu lineage”
“is the greatest of all warriors
and his charm as the emperor is unmatched”
Come on! Move in this way!
“The skies turn dark with fear as Bheema,
the lion of the Komuram clan”
“leaps up to attack his enemies.”
“Bheema, the lion of the Komuram clan”
Load.
Aim.
Shoot.
“He is the one mighty dancer under
whose graceful dancing feet”
“the heads of all the arrogant elephants
from the capital city Hasthina get crushed”
“Bheema, the lion of the Komuram clan”
Bheem.
How long do we hunt these jackals?
Let's hunt down the lion!
Load the canons.
Fire!
Bheem.
NO!!!
‘Promise me that you will give
every person a weapon.’
Made in an English factory, this bullet
has travelled the 7 seas in an English ship.
This is the bullet which is more valuable
than an Indian's life.
How can you throw it away?
Return it to him, Bheem.
Let him keep it in his heart.
Load!
No! No!!
Aim!
Shoot!
You’ve achieved it.
Bheem
you’ve taken me closer to my ambition.
You’ve given me this attire that will
inspire me through this quest.
What can I offer you in return?
Teach me how to read and write, brother.
“If your blood boils, lift up the flag”
“If your energy surges, crush the mountains”
“Flag - Rock - Sword - Hammer
Man - Harvest - Horn - Bull”
“Untamable bull from Ongole”
“Wealthy bull from Sirisilla”
“The bull that is supreme in its ability”
“The Rayalaseema bull is stronger than boulders”
“If your blood boils, lift up the flag”
“If your energy surges, crush the mountains”
Hey, look, everybody!
Our brother has returned!
“The burning blood asks you to rise”
“Wind rushes to your lungs as your chest
swells with pride”
“As your nerves of steel clench up,”
“The age of darkness has come to an end finally”
“If not now then when will you play?”
“The triumphant beats of drums
should resound majestically”
“Beat-call-new-fort
- bullet-hunt-forest-bull”
“The gritty bull from Kolkata”
“The Gujarati bull which is extraordinary”
“The sharpest bull from Kithooru”
“There's no match to the thirunalveli bull”
“If your blood boils, lift up the flag”
“If your energy surges, crush the mountains”
Mother!
Malli!
‘Water Forest Land’
“Tighten the turban on your head”
“Clenchen your fists - clench them harder”
“Announce your victory to the world”
“Every voice of ours is equal to a million”
“Look Mallesha, there's newfound courage
in your heart”
“Smile now Ganesha, start celebrating with joy”
“Joy - Laughter - Celebration - Festivity
Birth - Seed - Gold - Bull”
“The Punjabi bull has emotion in its heart”
“The Tanguturi bull refuses to bow down”
“The Pazhassi bull is the most valiant”
“The great Maratha bull makes waves of valor
in the ocean of history”
“We are not going to bow down to anyone”
“This festival of life is yours and mine”
“There are flaming torches stacked all around us”
“Become a revolution, and sound your battlecry”
“Sound off the drums, announce to every village”
“that the festival has finally arrived
to fill our gleeful eyes”
“The massive drums should boom in celebration”
“Dance rhythmically to your heart's content”
“Let the deer that lives on the moon dance with joy”
“Let the stars come and settle on our earth”
“If your blood boils, lift up the flag”
“If your energy surges, crush the mountains”